Now, we're about to get to YOLO mode,
which is great fun and where a lot of
the pizzazz is right now. But I do want
to keep things balanced by giving you
some of the the other counterpoints as
well. And one of them is this great blog
post by Anthropic. They always have
great blog posts. This one is about how
AI assistance impacts coding skills
formation. And really, this speaks to
that point I just made about junior
engineers and how important it is that
you keep learning. I thought this was a
very thoughtful post by anthropic
because it's clearly kind of it's it's
anti-anthropic in a way. It's it's been
very balanced and and what they what
they do is they they study um a room
full of junior coders and and that are
using AI assistants to help with a task
and those that are not using AI
assistants and at the end of it they
they find that there is a significant
difference in how the population
understood the underlying technology. a
library that they got to use. They gave
a quiz to both parties and um the people
that used AI averaged 50% on the quiz
and the others the people that did not
use AI average 67%.
And their point was that that the AI
only had a small actual productivity
improvement in this case because of the
type of challenge, but it had a
significant detrimental effect on the
learning ability of the junior
developers that were working on this.
And so that's a sobering point that we
should all keep in mind. And another
sobering point which is particularly
relevant for yoloing comes here in the
form of this article. Jellyfin is a
popular open-source media streaming
platform uh that that lots of people
contribute to and they put out this
policy for people who contribute code to
JellyFin that are using AI to generate
the code. AI assisted development. They
have a policy on it. Let me show you a
few things about it. Okay. In the first
paragraph, it says, "The rise of LMS has
been significant. The power and
flexibility of clawed code given a lot
of functionality to experienced and new
developers, but there are tradeoffs." It
says, there we have it. It says, "We are
seeing a precipitous rise in
contributors using AI within the
Jellyfin ecosystem as well as criticism
and concern about LLMs generally." And
uh it says uh these are going to lay out
the policy to address what we expect and
desire. Okay. What is this policy? First
of all, LLM output is prohibited for
them in direct communication like
writing issues or comments, feature
requests, pull requests, forum posts
with the exception of translations. It's
great that they said that. They have an
interesting catch there that you can
read, but it's great that they said
that. So, of course, it's good to
translate and you should say that you're
translating. Uh, it's good to do that
with an LLM. It's when people generate
content with LLMs, it's like the PR, why
why they're doing it or what they're
doing, that is something which which
just generates extra work and noise for
everyone around them. Okay, so that's
about communication. What about the
actual code? So, I'm going to read this
out verbatim because I think it's
important that we all hear this and and
keep this take take this to heart. The
use of LLMs for code is controversial
and open to much interpretation. These
guidelines are our best effort attempts
to ensure that knowledgeable developers
who seek to use these tools as
legitimate aid are not overly hindered
while also preventing a flood of slop
contributions that violate our core
ethos.
Wow. Okay. What what are these these
rules then? So, first of all,
contribution should be concise and
focused. If it claims to target X is
touching unrelated Y and Zed, it will be
rejected.
Okay. A PR must be broken to small
manageable commits. A PR is the name of
like like a change request. Formatting
and quality standards must be upheld. Do
not commit LLM meta files like Claude or
or of course agents.mmd.
You must review the output and be able
to explain it yourself without LLM
output. You need to be able to explain
it. What is being changed and why? If
you can't explain what the LLM did, we
are not interested in the change. How
about that? And now the other ones are
actually all common sense stuff. You
must test it. You must be able to take
feedback. You must have an in-depth
level of understanding. And the final
discretion is with the reviewers. And it
ends with the golden rule is this. Do
not just let an LLM loose on the
codebase with a vague VI prompt and then
commit the results as is. This is lazy
development and will always result in a
poor quality contribution from our
perspective and we are not at all
interested in such slop. Make an effort
or please do not bother and again you
are free to use LMS to assist you but
not as a sole source of code changes.
And there's lots of interesting stuff
about about how they would go about
enforcing this, particularly saying it's
it's not their their place to try and
evaluate whether something is LLM
generated or not. And it doesn't matter
if it is. What matters is the quality of
what it produces. The reason I take you
through this, I think this is actually
really well written. I think it is brave
of them to be so upfront about it and
put in writing what a lot of us feel
which is this this sense of the the
asymmetry that it is so easy to generate
tons of LLM code and then just submit it
out somewhere and the onus falls on the
senior people then to go through it and
try and digest it and understand what's
what's what's real what's the signal and
what's the noise and see through these
endless readmes me with lots of emojis
It's it's that that's how that's how the
weight has shifted. And that's not fair.
It needs to shift back. The people that
are generating the code, which is going
to be you and me for the next two and a
half weeks, it's up to us to generate
concise good code that we understand
back to front. And so, whilst today is
all about YOLO, and I it's great fun and
I encourage it, it needs to be done very
much in this spirit. The code needs to
come from us. We need to own the code.
And with these trade-offs firmly in mind
and with a mantra that we own the code,
I am still a massive fan of course of
using coding agents to build code. We'll
be doing so to great effect over the
next few weeks. And at all points, we
will be owning the code. And so now
we're going to do some real yoloing
after after all of this naysaying. We're
going to go and let a model at it. A few
things to keep in mind. First of all,
everything that I do is optional. You
can do different things if you want.
This is a choose your own adventure
moment. Take it in what direction you
want. Your results might be completely
different and that's okay. That's that's
what this is about. And if you've hit
problems, the trick is to simplify. Just
pair things back. Delete everything.
Start again with a simpler mandate. Keep
it as simple as possible. Always keep
that in mind. With that, we are going to
go and build our project. Let me tell
you about it and then we'll go and do
it. So for this incredibly simple
project, we are going to build a
personal portfolio website complete with
a digital twin, something I cover in
many of my other courses. A chatbot that
can answer questions about you and your
career, like a complete robust
portfolio, personal site, digital twin,
all in one go. We're gonna do it vibe
coding with YOLO so that we do nothing.
We just set it off and let it go. That's
the plan. And to start with, we need to
actually So, this is going to be a
coding agent that's building something
which is going to have AI in it as well.
It's a bit confusing. It's an an AI
building AI. So, we are going to need to
set up an ability for you to make AI
calls in the cloud, which you might have
done before a lot of times or it might
be the very first time you're doing it.
And I'm going to suggest that we use a
platform called Open Routter because it
allows you to access free models and
paid models. and it's super easy to use.
So that's what we're going to go and set
up right now. But if you're already an
OpenAI user and that's what you use and
you've got an account and you've got
credits and an API key, we can just use
that too. You if you do that, then you
know exactly how it works and just
simply replace Open Routter with OpenAI.
But for the people that are doing this
for the first time, let's go to Open
Routter right now. I'm going to take you
to their website which is open.ai.
Let's go there now. So open router is
this great service a provider which lets
you call different frontier models in
the cloud. Back in the day, if you
wanted to call models like OpenAI and
CLA and Anthropics Claude and Google's
Gemini, you needed to set up accounts
with each of those companies, you need
to put some money on there, like a pay
as you go money, a top up amount that
you put there, and you need to have like
an API key, which is like your password,
and connect to each one and and write
some code to do that. And Open Router
came along and said, "Hey, we we can be
the person in the middle. just have an
account with us and tell us which model
you want to call and we will route to
that model. And that's so convenient and
allows you to use free models in the
cloud or paid models all with one
account. Of course, if you are using
paid models, they do charge a small fee
for that when you as you do your top up
as as you will see, but it's worth it
because it's so convenient and that's
what we're going to use right now. And
it's going to also allow you to use free
models if that's what you'd like to do.
Okay, so I have gone to open router.ai
AI and you should as well and you should
see this and if you don't already have
an open router account then the first
thing to do is of course to press sign
up and then you come in and sign up and
you use your your uh Google credentials
if you have them or whatever you want to
have an account with open router and
then answer any questions it gives you
as part of the sign up process and then
you should get to the next screen. Here
I am after logging into open router and
on the top right is a usual kind of
avatar menu and here is a section called
keys and if I select this I go to this
this place that has my API keys and you
won't have any yet and you can press
this create API key button you can give
it a name that can be anything you want
just something to remember like like my
nice key but it can be whatever you want
if you if you're going to be using if
you're going to be putting on some money
cuz you want to is paid models. Then if
you wish, you can put a limit here as to
like I don't want to spend more than $5
a month. Then you could have it set like
this. Sorry, this is uh yeah, this is
the the dollar limit each month right
here. And you can also put an expiration
on the key should you want to do that.
And then you can create the key like
this. And it then gives you a key right
here. And you're going to copy it into
your clipboard. And you might want to
also save it just just somewhere
temporarily safe or if you have a
password manager, put it there. But copy
it into your clipboard. We're going to
need it in a minute. And here's the
thing, you don't want to mess this up.
Your key needs to be exactly this. It
needs to be this piece of text here,
including this this first sk--,
which stands for secret key and open
router-V1. This whole thing has to be
there. And if you get this wrong by a
single digit, then it won't work. And I
I I say this every time and and somehow
there's always a steady flow of of
people that that that have problems with
their keys because somewhere they've
messed up getting the key like this into
their their their code. And if it goes
wrong, then it won't work. If it doesn't
work, you can just come back and create
another key. You can have as many as you
want, but you'll have to create another
one, copy it, and then use it because
the key has to match. It has to be
exactly right. And you could keep this
screen up like this until we've pasted
it in where it needs to go in the next
part. Okay. And I'm I'm now going to
I've I've copied that. I'm now going to
close this down. I'm also going to
delete this so that because you've all
seen my key. So I've now deleted it. And
there's one more thing that I want to
set up in Open Router. If you're going
to be looking to use free models through
open router, then you need to come to
your avatar menu here, go to settings,
and then down here, go to privacy and
guard rails, and make sure these two
things here are turned on. Enable free
endpoints that might train on inputs
because if you use models for free,
you're saying, "Okay, but you may use
this to to train on, otherwise they
won't." and then enable free endpoints
that may publish your prompts because
it's not if you're going to use free
models again then you're you're you're
giving up the privacy angle. So those
two things should be turned on should
you wish to use the free models in open
router. So that's one thing to be aware
of. And for those that would like to use
a strong model for your digital twin,
you can come to the avatar menu and go
to credits. And this is where you can
add some credits in here that you can
spend against. And whilst some of these
providers have a $5 minimum, Open
Routter is is much more friendly. Last
time I tried it at least, oh, I don't
have anything in here. Uh, last time it
was a $2 minimum. So, for just $2
minimum, you can then put that down and
then draw down against it. Super
convenient. Uh, so it, should you wish,
it's completely optional. You can put
some money on this. This is going to be
used by your digital twin to answer
career questions about you to people
that go to your website. Okay, with that
open router is set up. You have copied
the open router key into your clipboard.
Maybe you still have that open. You can
always create more API keys if you wish.
It's time for us to start coding.